Bulut Karakaya

bulutk@gmail.com | www.bulutk.com

Phone: +44 (7470) 890039 | Skype: bulutkarakaya

Career Objective

I'm an ambitious gameplay programmer with 10+ years of experience. My focus areas are core gameplay and networking using Unity and Unreal engines. Previously, I was a co-founder/entrepreneur for indie games in Istanbul and currently, I use my expertise in larger teams to create inspiring games in the UK.

Work Experience

July 2018 - Present	Senior Gameplay Programmer - Jagex Ltd, Cambridge, United Kingdom
	• Working on an unannounced Action-RPG game using Unreal Engine 4.
	Working on combat loop including player character and AI.
	• Collaborating with game designers to on the design requirements and break it down into engineering tasks.
	 Creating proposals about maintaining and improving core gameplay systems.
March 2017 – June 2018	Lead Unity Programmer – Digit Game Studio, Dublin, Ireland
	 Worked on Star Trek: Fleet Command, for IOS and Android using Unity.
	 Responsible for creating technical plans and give time estimates for designs.
	 Break down plans into implementable chunks and assign it to programmers.
	 Have regular meetings with non tech teams, making sure their objectives are aligned with ours.
Oct 2016 - March 2017	Senior Unity Programmer - Digit Game Studio, Dublin, Ireland
	 Worked on Star Trek: Fleet Command, for IOS and Android.
Nov 2014 - May 2016	Cofounder / Technical Director – Pera Games, Istanbul, Turkey
	 Created Overfall a rogue-like RPG title for Steam using Unity.
	 Responsible for all the programming and creating the workflow for our non-technical team to can create
	characters, spells, environments and encounters without programmer input.
	 Organised and moderate some of the high-level game design meetings.
	 Launched the game on Steam, %93 positive feedback in the end of first month.
	 Presented Overfall at Unite'16 as a showcase game.
March 2014 - Sept 2014	Project Partner - GriPati Digital Entertainment, Istanbul, Turkey
	 Created Egg Fight a multiplayer fast paced fighting game for IOS and Android.
	 Responsible for all the programming and partial game design.
	 Used Unity to create the game client and GameSparks for backend.
Jan 2013 - Feb 2014	Cofounder / Technical Director - Tart Games, Istanbul, Turkey
	 Created Kixel a multiplayer 3d soccer game for Facebook and IOS.
	• Kixel reached over 2 million users in one year.
	 Responsible for most of the gameplay programming and leading a team of 6 people.
	 Used Unity as our game engine and Node.js with MongoDB for backend.
Aug 2012 - April 2013	Software Engineer – Tart New Media, Istanbul, Turkey
	 Responsible for optimising and developing the backend of gamification engine.
	• Used Node.js with MongoDB.
	• Lead 2 junior programmers.
Sept 2010 - Dec 2011	Gameplay Programmer – Gravi, Istanbul, Turkey
	 Worked on Gravi Floor, an interactive play ground which features various mini-games.
	Created prototypes using Unity.
June 2009 - Aug 2009	Prototype Intern – Stupid Fun Club, Berkeley, USA
_	 Stupid Fun Club is an entertainment think tank company created by Will Wright
	• Worked on prototypes for unannounced projects using C# and XNA.
July 2007 - Sept 2007	Internship - Microsoft Corporation, Redmond, USA
-	• First intern accepted to US office from a Turkish university.
	• Worked as software developer in test for Microsoft Office
Education	
May 2010	Carnegie Mellon University (CMU) - Entertainment Technologies Center, Pittsburgh, U.S.A
<i>,</i> - 00	• Master Of Entertainment Technology (MET)
	• Created SurfaceScapes, a D&D experience on Microsoft Surface table. Presented in GDC'10 and PAX East.
	• TA for Building Virtual Worlds course.
May 2008	Sabanci University (SU), Istanbul, Turkey
many 2000	and the control of th

Bachelor of Science degree in Computer Science and Engineering (CS)
 TA for VA433 3D Modeling and VA434 3D Animation course.

Bulut Karakaya – bulutk@gmail.com

Certificates

Aug 2020 Machine Learning - Stanford University (Coursera)

Skills

Proficient: C#, C++

Engines & Libraries: Unity, Unreal Engine 4

Version Control: Git, Perforce

Language: English (fluent), Turkish (Native)

Others: Maya, AfterEffects, PhotoShop (for programmer art)

Interests

Certified diver (Padi Advance), tango dancer since 2005, 6th degree Wing-Tsun practitioner, self taught snowboarder. I also practice aerial acrobacy (Trapeze), juggle, play games (Link) and read (Link).